#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-susmanb5bba311 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Financial Analysis
Transaction Analysis
Relationship Management

#### Certifications

Working Remotely

# Jeff Susman

Senior Credit Officer at Fifth Third Bank

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

## Summary

I am a highly accomplished professional who has been recognized for an exemplary work ethic and has repeatedly been promoted to roles of progressive responsibility. I am able to leverage analytical skills to address issues while increasing quality of unit's productivity. I offer visionary leadership to the bank and I aid clients' efforts in developing and analyzing financial alternatives. I am an experienced talent developer who builds multi-department transaction teams to successfully meet organizational goals.

## Experience

Fifth Third Bank
Senior Credit Officer
May 2020 - Present (3 months)
Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

#### BBVA in the USA

10 years 7 months

Director of Wholesale Credit Risk Management October 2016 - November 2019 (3 years 2 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Managed all facets of controlling credit risks of \$69B U.S. wholesale portfolio. Guided team of ~200 professionals regarding underwriting, approving, monitoring, and controlling portfolio. Supervised Workout Unit, Credit Policy Unit, Credit Administration, and Tools & Models Team. Retained working partnerships and lines of communication with risk colleagues and risk leadership in head office. Attended monthly meetings of Risk Committee of the board of directors; made presentations on all facets of the Wholesale portfolio.

Director of Corporate & Investment Banking Credit Risk 2014 - October 2016 (2 years)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Administered all aspects of credit risks of \$28B U.S. corporate & investment banking segment portfolio. Directed team of ~30 professionals for underwriting,

approving, monitoring, and managing portfolio. Focused on increasing interactions and relationships with risk colleagues in head office. Attended monthly meetings of Risk Committee of the board of directors; made presentations on all facets of CIB portfolio.

Credit Risk Officer
May 2009 - 2014 (5 years)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Oversaw all primary commercial and corporate borrowers and prospective borrowers. Maintained positive relationships with client managers, underwriters, business leaders, loan syndication personnel, and risk colleagues in head office. Integral figure of organizational team pushing plan to boost commercial portion of portfolio and to reduce portfolio concentrations of real estate loans. Contributed to portfolio mix changing from 33% commercial loans to 50% commercial loans from 2009 to 2013.

Bank of America
20 years 7 months

Senior Vice President
April 2002 - February 2009 (6 years 11 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Corporate Debt Products - Led the Gaming & Leisure industry sector team since April, 2004 responsible for originating, structuring, underwriting, and monitoring of all credit commitments to the corporate clients and prospects in the sector. Responsible for a team of credit risk professionals and a loan portfolio of \$4.4Bn in commitments and \$2.7Bn in utilizations. In addition, served as Chairman of the Risk Rating Scorecard Issues Committee which dealt with issues of internally assigned risk ratings and conformance with regulatory requirements. Other industry sectors covered include Natural Resources and Retail.

Senior Vice President
April 2000 - April 2002 (2 years 1 month)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Senior Client Manager in Commercial Banking - Led customer relationships with Southwest regionally based companies with annual revenues between \$100 million and \$1 billion to provide strategic financial solutions including lending, syndications, private debt placements, treasury services, interest rate risk management, foreign exchange, and private client services.

Principal

April 1997 - April 2000 (3 years 1 month)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Senior Structurer in Loan Syndications responsible for structuring and managing the execution of syndicated credit facilities for large corporate clients in various industry sectors including technology, distribution, lodging, entertainment, energy, retail, and transportation.

Senior Vice President August 1988 - April 1997 (8 years 9 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Relationship Manager and Credit Products Officer in Corporate Banking - Led corporate customer relationships with Southwest regionally based companies with annual revenues of at least \$250 million to provide strategic financial solutions including lending, syndications, public and private debt, treasury management, interest rate risk management, and foreign exchange.

## Education

Southern Methodist University - Cox School of Business Master of Business Administration - MBA

The University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Arts (BA)